<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>8thgrades on Terrace Community Middle School</title>
    <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 8thgrades on Terrace Community Middle School</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:18:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost/8thgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Technology in Business</title>
      <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:18:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/8thgrade/technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course is designed to teach emerging technology and the effects of its application on society. Instruction is designed to provide an understanding of the advances being made in technology today and in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This program offers a sequence of project-based assignments that provide coherent and rigorous content aligned with challenging academic standards and relevant technical knowledge and skills needed to prepare for further education and careers in Technology. The content includes but is not limited to practical experiences in game/simulation conceptualization, design, storyboarding, 2D/3D animation design, production and implementation issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course will enable students to apply knowledge and skills in computer applications to the design, presentation, and evaluation of specified projects. This course is designed to enable students to develop basic knowledge of the functions, capabilities, applications, and social implications of the Internet. This program involves students in constructing objects to gain manipulative skills and technical knowledge. The students will learn to communicate via photography, computer presentations, public speaking, and audiovisual productions. Recording, speaking, and production techniques will be taught; as well as to operate audiovisual and media-related equipment. The students will be using the design process to formulate solutions to a range of design challenges. Projects may include digital videos, slide shows, web design, and flash animation. Students will plan, evaluate, and demonstrate appropriate use of technology in the area of multimedia and interactive communications. Group activities and hands-on projects are an essential component of this course. This is a semester long course and it is also a &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; credit high school elective class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Materials Fee: $10.00&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish I Honors High School Credit</title>
      <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:18:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/8thgrade/spanish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites: Upon recommendation of Language Arts teachers and test scores/ Based on student’s performance in the 7th grade Spanish course (B or higher)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this course is to enable students to continue the proficiency in Spanish through a linguistic, communicative and cultural approach to language learning. The student is introduced to various sections of the language where they will be able to communicate using learned vocabulary dealing with general topics such as: greetings, family, weather expressions, home setting, pastimes, food items, leisure activities, sports, and places in the community, ordering in a restaurant, map skills, locations, shopping and much more. The student will be able to interpret many aspects of grammar, reading, speaking, listening and writing skills. The student will also elaborate and write short essays on numerous topics. Cultural activities and cross-curricular activities will play a major role. Skits will be presented to portray real-life Hispanic situations. The student will be able to identify many pictures and will be able to increase his or her listening skills through video and language drills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year long course for high school credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Course activity fee: $17.00 (workbook)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:18:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/8thgrade/music/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;tcms-band-1&#34;&gt;TCMS Band 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCMS BAND 1 is designed for students who are new to the band or students with limited music backgrounds. Students will learn musical notation and the technique for playing their instrument. Students will select instruments during the first quarter to be played throughout the year. This is a great ensemble for students to begin their musical experiences. This is a year-long course for 6th, 7th or 8th grade students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Course Fee: Instrument rental cost, concert dress cost as necessary and $15 materials fee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;tcms-chrous&#34;&gt;TCMS Chrous&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCMS CHORUS is the vocal course for all choral students at TCMS, regardless of level or experience. The mixed chorus sings a variety of literature from standard vocal repertoire, jazz, popular and musical theatre. Students also learn basic music theory and sight singing. In the spring the mixed chorus has the opportunity to participate in the TCMS Spring Musical. This is a year-long course for 6th, 7th and 8th grade students. No audition is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Course Fee: $10 Sheet Music, concert dress cost as needed&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/8thgrade/art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will be a semester long course that incorporates two-dimensional, hands-on activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover a variety of sources of inspiration for visual art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin to develop a general understanding of the various artists acquire and transform ideas into visual form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore appropriate media, technology, forms and methods for visual expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop skills for using appropriate tools, technology, materials and techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin to apply their understanding of the elements of art and the principles of design when discussing, analyzing, developing and reflecting on works of art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge themselves to solve visual art problems in a variety of new ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Course Materials Fee $10.00&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. History &amp; Career Planning (Honors)</title>
      <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/geography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:17:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/8thgrade/geography/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;focus-exploration-through-the-modern-era&#34;&gt;Focus: Exploration through the Modern Era&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their last year at TCMS, students will begin their study of American History. At this level, students are introduced to the political, geographic, and the socioeconomic forces that have shaped our country. Students will also continue their education of American Civics, which will ultimately help prepare them for the roles and responsibilities required of every American citizen. To help bring this information to life, students will engage in debates, hear lectures, and perform reenactments of historical events. Eighth grade students will also focus on document based questioning, which will require them to read and comprehend a primary or secondary source and then extrapolate the larger historical meanings from the reading. Such skills will enable students to make a smooth transition to the high school AP or IB courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;field-trips-and-out-of-classroom-experiences&#34;&gt;Field Trips and Out of Classroom Experiences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the in-class curriculum, students will have the opportunity to participate in a truly amazing trip to Washington DC or Tallahassee. For those students going to our nation’s capital, they will visit Fords Theater, the White House, and visit many important and historical monuments. Students will also participate in a culminating project which will require them to research the life of a fallen soldier. Thus, the students will not simply be visiting the Vietnam Memorial. Instead, such research will allow them to reflect on the personal sacrifices others have made, sacrifices that have made our country into what it is today. For students going to Tallahassee, they will tour the new and old capitol, participate in a community service project, visit the Florida Supreme Court, tour the Florida History Museum and visit Mission San Luis. Students will also do a culminating project which will enable them to synthesize the role the first permanent European settlement had in our history.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Science (Honors)</title>
      <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:17:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/8thgrade/science/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Students in the 8th grade science program at TCMS are taught the high school level Physical Science Honors Curriculum. This rigorous high school equivalent science course meets the requirements for graduation under the Florida Academic Scholars Program. This course is inquiry based and students are expected to build science knowledge by formulating questions, making predictions, conducting experiments, analyzing and interpreting data and drawing conclusions. Hands-on laboratory experiments are an integral part of this course. The main focus of the curriculum will be on the chemical and physical sciences including but not limited to: volume and mass, conservation of mass, characteristic properties of matter, mixtures, compounds and elements, the periodic table, radioactivity, force and motion, Newton’s Laws, energy and energy transfers, and waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-science-honors-credit&#34;&gt;Physical Science Honors Credit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quarters 1 and 2 will count for 75% and the semester exam will count for 25% of the overall semester grade. Second semester credit will be determined by using quarters 3 and 4 (75%) and the second semester exam score (25%). Students must earn 3 quality points each semester to earn HS credit (this includes the semester exam). Students are not permitted to change the level of their course once the school year has begun. Students who do not meet the requirements (at least 3 quality points) to receive high school credit will not have the option to move into a MJ3A Advanced 8th grade science course. The grades earned in Physical Science Honors will transfer with the student on their high school transcript if the student enrolls in a public high school and will affect the high school GPA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Language Arts</title>
      <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/languagearts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:17:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/8thgrade/languagearts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Eighth grade Language Arts students are expected to refine and extend all skills introduced in grades 6 and 7. Students will still spend at least 30 minutes each night on homework, reading or study for Language Arts. Parental support will continue to be critical to student success since students will need time to study and will need Internet access (at home or a local public library). In eighth grade, students will read a minimum of five novels. Students also refine their literary analysis skills and advance their study of poetic structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All students will be expected to craft and write strong explanatory and argument essays in grade 7 and continue with this essential skill in grade 8. Students will also work towards strengthening their persuasive writing skills to prepare for the “on-demand writing season,” as students must write for magnet, IB and preparatory school admissions. E Eighth grade students also complete an argument based, cross-curricular research paper. The final draft must be typed and correctly formatted MLA style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will be expected to have mastered the basic concepts of word study, including word structures (prefixes, roots, and suffixes), grammar skills, and context clues. The workbook Grammar for Middle School: A sentence composing approach By Don and Jenny Killgallon is utilized. Vocabulary building will be incorporated into the curriculum through the 8th grade edition of the soft-text R.E.V. It Up. This in-class activity workbook provides relevant SAT vocabulary instruction through pictures and related critical thinking exercises. In addition, eighth grade Language Arts activities also include media productions in response to literature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within this curriculum students are expected and encouraged to master grade-level listening, speaking and viewing skills. This will mean collaborating in groups, making speeches, listening respectfully and actively, completing individual and group projects and analyzing movies and other genres of multi-media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional eighth grade Language Arts units include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;novels&#34;&gt;Novels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surviving Antarctica by Andrea White&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legend by Marie Lu
Topics/Themes explored: dystopian society, friendship/teamwork, roles of boys vs. girls, roles of class/ crossing class boundaries; Literary techniques (foreshadowing, irony, personification, plot, flashback)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chasing Lincoln’s Killer by James L. Swanson
Topics/Themes explored : Historical Non-fiction, Series of historical events in chronological order, Ideology, and perseverance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Separate Peace by John Knowles
Topics/Themes explored: jealously, envy between friends, loss of innocence, acceptance of others/tolerance, and War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Midsummer Night’s Dream by William Shakespeare
Topics/Themes explored: introduction to Shakespeare/biography, infatuation vs. love, meter/rhyme, iambic pentameter, poetry, and sonnet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanatory and Persuasive elements of writing: MLA research paper, grammar usage, spelling, mechanics, and vocabulary usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reading-comprehension&#34;&gt;Reading comprehension&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;context clues, main idea, author’s purpose, cause and effect, structure/organizational patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;literacy-across-the-curriculum&#34;&gt;Literacy Across the Curriculum&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At TCMS, all teachers are committed to teaching literacy.  Teachers are required to receive reading training each year to add to their teaching techniques and to refresh their reading instruction skills.  In addition, all teachers are required to implement reading strategies during classroom instruction. The continued reinforcement of reading strategies provides continuity in the classroom and gives students strategies they can apply in all disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;academic-support&#34;&gt;Academic Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Language Arts teachers provide diagnostic testing in reading to students at the beginning of each year. Based on this diagnostic testing and/or prior year FSA English/Language Arts scores, students who demonstrate specific reading challenges are selected for the TCMS 7th period intensive tutoring program for individual/small group reading instruction once a week. These students are monitored by their tutor and, monthly, by their Grade Level Administrator. During Skills tutoring, the following reading strategies are reintroduced and reinforced to improve reading comprehension:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-questioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making connections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualizing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowing how words work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring Self-comprehension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summarizing main ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building reading speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on students&amp;rsquo; needs and interests, teachers utilize materials (fiction and non-fiction) into this tutoring program. In addition to after school tutoring, these students are provided extra help throughout the school day by TCMS academic tutors. These small groups meet every week in order to practice and reinforce basic skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, in order to strengthen and implement advanced reading and writing skills, additional support for students is provided by all Language Arts teachers in every grade level before the regular school day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Mathematics</title>
      <link>http://localhost/8thgrade/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 10:17:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/8thgrade/math/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Students in the 8th grade math program at TCMS are taught the high school level Algebra I or Algebra I Honors curriculum. This rigorous, high school equivalent math course demands the best the student has to offer. Students must work hard at their grades each quarter and successfully pass a semester exam and the state End of Course Exam to qualify for a full high school credit. The Algebra curriculum focuses upon linear models, quadratic equations, exponential relationships, descriptive statistics, and polynomials. The Standards for Mathematical Practice apply throughout each course and, together with the content standards, prescribe that students experience mathematics as a coherent, useful, and logical subject that makes use of their ability to make sense of problem situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will have many opportunities to express their problem solving abilities through writing, collaboration, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;high-school-credit&#34;&gt;High School Credit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students in the 8th grade at TCMS are eligible for high school math credit. The requirements for a student to pass the first semester course are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The averaged letter grade for the first semester is based upon 70% from the first and second quarter averaged letter grade and 30% from the first semester exam. First semester credit is a prerequisite for second semester credit. Students must earn at least 3 quality points per semester.
Effective the 2011-2012 school year, a student enrolled in Algebra I for high school credit or Algebra I Honors for high school credit must pass the state End of Course Exam (EOC) administered in May. The EOC must be passed as determined by the state grading system for the student to earn their high school credit. It is possible that a student can pass the overall course, but not pass the EOC. That student would have to enroll in a summer make up EOC workshop or contact the high school where they will enroll in 9th grade to take the make-up exam offered the following December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Algebra I or Algebra I H credit is a prerequisite for the International Baccalaureate program in the District. The student must successfully complete both semester one and two of the math class for credit in order to attend this program in high school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>