<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Students on Terrace Community Middle School</title>
    <link>http://localhost/students/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Students on Terrace Community Middle School</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 18:35:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost/students/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Athletics</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/athletics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 18:35:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/athletics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the 2016-2017 academic school year! Through our Athletics program, we look forward to providing our students with extracurricular opportunities that are well-rounded and meet high standards for a competitive interscholastic athletic program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s sports offerings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;row table-responsive&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md-12&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class = &#34;table table-condensed table-hover table-bordered table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%;border: 2px solid black;padding: 10px;margin: 10px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr style=&#34;background-color:black; color:white&#34;&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Fall&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Winter&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Spring&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Boys Soccer&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Boys Basketball&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Girls Soccer&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Boys and Girls Cross Country &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Girls Basketball&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Boys Flag Football&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Girls Volleyball&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Boys Baseball&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-yw4l&#34;&gt;Girls Cheer&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-yw4l&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-yw4l&#34;&gt;Boys and Girls Track&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through involvement in our competitive athletic sports program at TCMS we aim for students to…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop physical skills and fitness through regular practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop an understanding of commitment and the value of dedicated practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embrace their interdependence and understand the need for team work as a pre-requisite for success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop leadership skills through distinct roles during the season.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trust and respect the value of good sportsmanship and practice it through their treatment of officials, peers, opponents, and spectators during activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have fun and use physical activity as a means of stress release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate courage by taking appropriate risks with the aim of self growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refine existing skills and learn new ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please remember to have your child turn in their Pre-Participation Physical before tryouts are held for the sport they are interested in trying out for. My hope is that the continued support from parents, student-athletes, coaches, and school personnel will make our competitive athletics a positive one in every way possible. For all those involved, TCMS thanks you for this. Good luck to all participants as we look forward to another great year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to contact me at: robert.negron@tcmstornadoes.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tcmstornadoes.com/services/ad-docs/Pre-Participation%20Sports%20Physical.pdf&#34;&gt;Required Physical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tcmstornadoes.com/services/ad-docs/old/VEHICLES%20LIST%202014-2015%209-2014.pdf&#34;&gt;Approved Vehicles List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tcmstornadoes.com/services/ad-docs/FAQ.pdf&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tcmstornadoes.com/services/ad-docs/Parent_Player_Agreement%2016-17-Cross%20Country.pdf&#34;&gt;Parent/Player Contract Cross Country&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tcmstornadoes.com/services/ad-docs/Parent_Player_Agreement%2016-17.pdf&#34;&gt;Parent/Player Contract VB-BB-FF-Soccer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tcmstornadoes.com/services/ad-docs/Game%20Locations.pdf&#34;&gt;Game Day Locations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:30:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/technology/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;TCMS has a BYOD (bring your own device) policy that allows students to use their own devices at the direction of their instructor within the guidelines of school policies. These devices include laptops, tablets, smart phones, and e-readers. Please consult your handbook for policies and procedures in regards to technology use. We do the best that we can to provide a safe and engaging learning environment for your student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;downloads&#34;&gt;Downloads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tcmstornadoes.com/rrmrc/nookdocs/T-130-TCMS_Digital_Equipment_User_Agreement.pdf&#34;&gt;T-130 TCMS Digital Equipment User Agreement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tcmstornadoes.com/13-14/Acceptable_Use_of_the_Student_Wireless_Access__TCMS__SWAT.pdf&#34;&gt;T-120 Technology Acceptable Use Policy and Parent Permission Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;2017-2020 TCMS Technology Plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tcmstornadoes.com/trs/mediareleaseform.pdf&#34;&gt;Media Release Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6th Grade Supply List</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/6thgradesupplylist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:30:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/6thgradesupplylist/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;6th-grade-supply-list&#34;&gt;6th Grade Supply List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7th Grade Supply List</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/7thgradesupplylist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:30:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/7thgradesupplylist/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;7th-grade-supply-list&#34;&gt;7th Grade Supply List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8th Grade Supply List</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/8thgradesupplylist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:30:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/8thgradesupplylist/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8th-grade-supply-list&#34;&gt;8th Grade Supply List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Center</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/mediacenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:30:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/mediacenter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology/media staff are available to assist with:
1.        Checking out/ operating Nooks
2.        Research assignments
3.·       Class assignments
4.·       Resource recommendations
5.·       Technology related to completing school assignments
6.·       Reference questions
7.·       Photocopying
8.        Opportunities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students may use the Technology/Media Center before and after school hours for studying individually or in small groups.&lt;br /&gt;
Computers are available for school assignments throughout the day with a pass.
Replacement I.D. cards can be purchased in the media center for $5.00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;expectations&#34;&gt;Expectations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food and drink are not allowed in the Technology/Media Center or near mobile Computer Labs. Students are expected to be courteous to one another and to the Technology/Media staff. To check out materials or use computers, students must show their school I.D. cards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exceptional Student Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/esegifted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:30:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/esegifted/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Exceptional Student Education Program at Terrace Community Middle School supervises, coordinates, and monitors school-wide ESE/ Gifted services and documents.  This is done in compliance with federal, state, and TCMS board policies and procedures.  We are assisted by the district with the identification, evaluation, and placement of eligible ESE students in the least restrictive environment.  In addition, ESE services offer support and assistance to faculty, staff, students, and parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a school of choice, TCMS and the ESE department provide services to ESE and gifted students that maximize their participation in our advanced and honors curriculum, offered in the general education classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ese-and-gifted-services-offered-at-tcms&#34;&gt;ESE and Gifted Services Offered at TCMS:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gifted students with an Education Plan (EP), who demonstrate the need for an accelerated curriculum, have services provided through advanced/honors content courses taught within the regular education classroom setting. These courses are taught by teachers who have earned, or signed ‘intent to earn’, gifted teacher endorsement. Instruction is fast paced, and differentiated, with enrichment through research, projects, Math League, Battle of the Books, and Forensics. See subject area curriculum guides for further information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For ESE students with an Individual Education Plan (IEP), performing on grade level, monthly consultative services are offered.  Consult services allow us to monitor skills maintenance and progress towards satisfactory mastery of student IEP goals.  It also ensures proper monitoring of IEP instructional and testing accommodations implemented in the general education classroom.  ESE and Regular education teachers conduct a monthly face-to face meeting to discuss student performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For students found eligible for an ESE program with an IEP who are performing below grade level, and require remediation in reading, math, or writing, weekly small group direct instruction in learning strategies is offered. Small group direct instruction is provided during student elective periods by ESE certified teachers.  See ESE curriculum guide for further information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekly Speech and Language therapy is provided by a licensed speech pathologist that is privately contracted through Beth Ingram and Associates.  Therapy is provided during student elective periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IF YOUR CHILD HAS AN IEP, it is extremely important and highly encouraged, that you contact the ESE Specialist in order to discuss his or her individual ESE needs with the IEP team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programs for English Language Learners</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/ellesl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:29:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/ellesl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The English For Speakers of Other Languages program at the middle school level enrolls linguistically and culturally diverse secondary students, who require intensive structured English language instruction and orientation to a new cultural and academic environment. Students at TCMS are assessed on a state-mandated test of language proficiency and placed in an appropriate level of ESOL instruction level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of ELL/ESOL instruction is the development of language proficiency through speaking, listening, reading and writing English. Students develop competency in English, orally practicing correct English grammar as they express social and academic needs and in logically organizing and clearly expressing their ideas in written English. Students explore an understanding of the human experience from a multicultural perspective as they develop reading and writing skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students read developmentally appropriate texts representing the genres of narration, poetry, drama and exposition. As students become more fluent with spoken and written English, they increase their familiarity with academic vocabulary and they learn to analyze text and develop critical reading and thinking skills. The development of these language skills and processes also help students prepare for local, state and national assessments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English Language Learner – a student who:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was not born in the U.S. and whose native language is other than English; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was born in the U.S. but who comes from a home in which a language other than English is most relied upon for communication; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is an American Indian or Alaskan Native and comes from a home in which a language other than English has had a significant impact on his or her level of English Language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who as a result of the above, has sufficient difficulty speaking, reading, writing, or
understanding the English language to deny him or her the opportunity to learn successfully in
classrooms in which the language of instruction is English.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counseling</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/counseling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:29:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/counseling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My job as the school counselor at TCMS is to support our students through their journey through middle school, which at times can be can be quite challenging for them. I am able to provide assistance in the areas of academic, personal/social, career, and Multicultural/Global Citizenship Development.  If your child is having any sort of issue or difficulty, please don’t hesitate to call me at 987-6555, #302 or email me at jessica.wahnon@tcmstornadoes.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s set our kids up for success this year! Here are some basic guidelines to help your child get off on the “right foot” this year in middle school&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend school every day unless ill, and get to school on time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get plenty of sleep each night (8 – 10 hours).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat a healthy breakfast each morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay attention in class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down assignments daily in TCMS planner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start projects with plenty of time for completion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete homework assignments on time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for help when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read for fun as well as for school!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though middle school children may act like they wish their parents would disappear at times, they still need you around. Research shows that student achievement improves when parents stay actively involved in their child’s education. Ask them what they are learning each day, talk about their homework assignments and show them that you think learning is important.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinic</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/clinic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:29:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/clinic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are asking you for your continued cooperation in assisting us to control the spread of communicable diseases. Our goal is to make our school a healthy, safe place for both students and staff. We will call you immediately if your child becomes ill during school hours. You are expected to arrange for your child to be picked up AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE after receiving our call. Our school clinic is not equipped or staffed to handle ill children for long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please inform us IMMEDIATELY if telephone numbers or other information on your child’s emergency card changes. The information on this card is vital for the safety and well being of your child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WE ASK YOU NOT SEND YOUR CHILD TO SCHOOL IF ANY SIGNS/SYMPTOMS LISTED BELOW ARE PRESENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vomiting or diarrhea within past 24 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fever within past 24 hours (100 degrees or higher WITHOUT the use of fever reducing medicine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sore/red throat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persistent coughing or sneezing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red watery eyes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earache, drainage from ear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excessive mucus from nose (runny nose), particularly greenish-yellow mucus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your child may return to school as soon as ALL SIGN/SYMPTOM ARE GONE or when your physician provides a WRITTEN STATEMENT indicating your child is ready to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your child has a communicable disease, please call and tell us the nature of the illness and when we can expect his/her return to school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cafe</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 17:29:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/cafe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lunches are ordered online each month through &lt;a href=&#34;http://schoolcode.orgsonline.com&#34;&gt;http://schoolcode.orgsonline.com&lt;/a&gt;. Our school code is 46TCMSFL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lunch orders are placed online between the 5th and the 15th of each month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Returning families/students will use the same email/password as last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Families new to TCMS will be sent the code in their Grade Level Packets at the end of May.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Families with dual enrollment with Jesuit can use the same sign on. After login in please go to the left side of the screen and select dual enrollment to add your child to your current account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AFTER you complete the online order form, please come back to this page to pay via Paypal (BUY NOW) button below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have a Paypal account, and wish to send money directly, send funds to linda.shivers@tcmstornadoes.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you do not have Internet access: print form available upon student request in the cafeteria. You may pay by check -please make checks payable to TCMS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After School Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost/students/afterschoolcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 16:03:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/students/afterschoolcare/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;program-overview&#34;&gt;Program Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terrace Community Middle School (TCMS) Afterschool Program provides structured activities (snack time, study time and free time which includes arts, crafts, indoor and outdoor games, etc.) in a school-based setting. Our program begins as soon as school is dismissed and continues until 6:00 p.m. on all regular school days, including early dismissal days. Please note, however, that we will not offer this program on the LAST DAY OF SCHOOL. All students must be picked up at dismissal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strive to keep our staff ratio at 1:15. The cost of our program is $50 per week, or $10 per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;application&#34;&gt;Application&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A $40 non-refundable application/membership fee must accompany this application and Contact Information/Emergency Form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;payments&#34;&gt;Payments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Payment can be made by check, money order, debit, charge card or by Paypal. No cash will be accepted. Payments are due the week services are rendered or either by payment in advance. This service is a privilege, and if payment is not received timely, this privilege can be revoked and you will have to make arrangements to have your child picked up timely following school dismissal. If there is a hardship, you need to speak with the principal or business manager to make other financial arrangements. A $25 fee will be charged for any returned checks. In accordance with the Student Handbook, if two checks are returned due to NSF, you will only be allowed to make payment by money order, debit, charge or PayPal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;holidays&#34;&gt;Holidays&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Afterschool Program will not be held on any non-student day which includes holidays, teacher planning days, etc. Please refer to the school calendar for these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dismissal-authorized-persons&#34;&gt;Dismissal/Authorized Persons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an authorized person picks up your child, they MUST:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the program area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show photo I.D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign out the child every day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ONLY those persons listed on the child&amp;rsquo;s emergency card will be authorized to pick up the child. No one else, including family members, is considered an authorized person. If there is any doubt, phone verification will be made to the child&amp;rsquo;s parent before any child is released. In the event the parent cannot be reached, the child WILL NOT be released. Should any authorized person arrive to pick up a child and they appear to be under the influence of drugs or alcohol, for the child&amp;rsquo;s safety, staff may have no recourse but to contact the police and not allow the child to leave with that person. Please do not put staff in a position where they have to make this judgment call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;late-pick-up&#34;&gt;Late Pick Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important that you make arrangements for your child to be picked up no later than 6:00 p.m. A LATE FEE of $10 per 15 minute intervals will be assessed after 6:00 p.m. REPEATED LATENESS IS CAUSE FOR DISMISSAL FROM THE PROGRAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;safety-procedures&#34;&gt;Safety Procedures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note there will not be a nurse on the premises during the Afterschool Program. Children suffering injury at or during the Afterschool Program will be brought to the Program Director for necessary care, or if the injury appears serious, the child will remain at the scene of the injury and will be given first aid to avoid further injury or complication. The parent or guardian will be notified at the time of the injury or illness and given the option of picking up their child at that time. If not available, the child&amp;rsquo;s physician and/or emergency contact will be notified. In the event of serious injury, emergency personnel (911) will be contacted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;discipline-policy&#34;&gt;Discipline Policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children will be required to follow the same rules and responsibilities for conduct as outlined in the TCMS Student Handbook during the Afterschool Program. The discipline policy outlined in the Student Handbook will be followed in this program as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Afterschool Program is a privilege and a convenience for our school families. Please note that if a student either enrolled in the program or as a drop-in is deemed to be a threat to themselves or another person associated with the program, or continually disrupts the program as it is intended and scheduled, that student and their family will lose the right to utilize the program. If a student is asked not to come back to the program, they may also lose their privilege of participating in afterschool activities, as the Afterschool Program is used for students who are not picked up immediately following the after school activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;medication-illness&#34;&gt;Medication/Illness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Afterschool Program will not dispense medication without written permission from the parent or legal guardian. If your child has a contagious condition (i.e. pink eye, lice, fever, rash, etc.) he/she will not be admitted into the program during that period. You will be required to pick up your child immediately. All medication must be in its original container with the child&amp;rsquo;s name, doctor&amp;rsquo;s name and dosage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;staff-transportation&#34;&gt;Staff Transportation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Afterschool staff is not authorized or allowed to transport children from the program to another location for any reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;contacting-the-program-director&#34;&gt;Contacting the Program Director&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to contact the Program Director, please call 813-230-2630. This is the cell phone number that the Program Director will have at all times so you won&amp;rsquo;t have to through the school office after dismissal of school.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>